<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		<h4>Characteristics Extension</h4><a>   </a>
		<p> The <code>characteristic</code> extension is a loosely defined key–value pair that allows
			implementations to add any other information about the medicinal product. Such
			information may include details relevant to requests (for example lactose-free = true)
			or additional data about the product actually dispensed (for example special precaution
			for storage = "Store in a refrigerator (2°C – 8°C)"). The data type of the value depends
			on the type of the characteristic. </p>
		<p> Availability of this information depends on its presence in the source data. In FHIR, <code>
			MedicationKnowledge</code> and resources in the Medication Definition module
			include elements for characteristics or properties, which allow medicinal product
			dictionaries to communicate this type of data when necessary. Other elements in detailed
			product descriptions may also be conveyed using this extension. </p>
		<h4>Strength Representation with basisOfStrengthSubstance Extension</h4><a>   </a>
		<p> The <code>basisOfStrengthSubstance</code> extension is used when the substance listed as
			the ingredient differs from the substance on which the strength is expressed. </p>
		<p> In many medicinal products, the ingredient may be represented as a precise substance
			(for example a salt form), while the strength is expressed in terms of the active
			moiety. When the ingredient substance and the strength reference substance do not match,
			the <code>basisOfStrengthSubstance</code> extension indicates which substance the
			strength value refers to. </p>
		<p>
			The following examples represent different representations of the concept:
		</p>
		<p>
			<i>1193768007 | Product containing precisely cefuroxime (as cefuroxime sodium) 750
				milligram/1 vial powder for conventional release solution for injection (clinical
				drug)|</i>
		</p>
		<p>
			Depending on the medicinal product dictionary, the substance and strength provided may
			differ.
		</p>
		<p>
			If the ingredient substance and the strength refer to the same substance, the extension
			can be
			used for explicit clarity, but it does not add additional information.
		</p>
		<table border="1">
			<tr>
				<th>Data element</th>
				<th>Example 1</th>
				<th>Example 2</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Ingredient</td>
				<td>cefuroxime</td>
				<td>cefuroxime sodium</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Strength</td>
				<td>750 mg</td>
				<td>789 mg</td>
			</tr>
		</table>
		<p>
			If the ingredient is a different form of the substance (for example a salt), but the
			strength is
			expressed for another substance (typically the active moiety), the extension is needed
			to remove
			this ambiguity.
		</p>
		<table border="1">
			<tr>
				<th>Data element</th>
				<th>Example 3</th>
				<th>Example 4</th>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Ingredient</td>
				<td>cefuroxime</td>
				<td>cefuroxime sodium</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>Strength</td>
				<td>789 mg</td>
				<td>750 mg</td>
			</tr>
			<tr>
				<td>basisOfStrengthSubstance</td>
				<td>cefuroxime sodium</td>
				<td>cefuroxime</td>
			</tr>
		</table>
		<p>
			The approach described here aligns with the SNOMED CT medicinal product concept model
			and can
			be derived from the ISO IDMP representation.
		</p>
		<h4>Medicinal Product Name</h4><a>   </a>
		<p> The <code>Medication</code> resource does not include an explicit element for the
			medicinal product name. In countries where medication information is distributed as a
			code system, the de facto elements used for holding the medication name have been <code>
			Medication.code.text</code> or <code>Medication.code.coding.display</code>. This is also
			the recommendation of HL7 Pharmacy. </p>
		<p> However, analysis of extensions in national implementation guides showed that many
			countries prefer to extend the <code>Medication</code> resource in order to include an
			explicit element for the authorised name of the product. It is also evident that
			countries often add multiple codings to the <code>.code</code> element, which makes it
			difficult to understand which coding is associated with the official product name. </p>
		<p> Therefore, this implementation guide includes a simple extension for the authorised
			medicinal product name. National implementations are not required to use this extension
			when their functional requirements are covered by the <code>.code</code> element. </p>
		<h4>Identifier vs Code</h4><a>   </a>
		<p> In case of medications, the line between <code>.identifier</code> and <code>.code</code>
			is not always clear, and the practice of using these elements differs between countries. </p>
		<p> This implementation guide allows the use of the <code>.identifier</code> element for
			non-instance identifiers such as IDMP identifiers or product codes from a national
			product registry or EMA PMS. It should be noted that identifiers do not have display
			names, which requires the consumer of the data to have lookup access to the source
			system of the identifier or the producer of the data to populate additional descriptive
			elements describing the product. </p>
		<h4>Code vs Classification (e.g. ATC)</h4><a>   </a>
		<p> The <code>classification</code> extension was introduced after reviewing how
			different countries implement medication classifications. Some implementations include
			ATC codes in <code>Medication.code.coding</code>, while others use extensions. </p>
		<p>
			Because classifications such as ATC represent a categorisation of a medication rather
			than the
			medication itself, the preferred approach is to convey them in a separate classification
			element.
		</p>
		<p>
			National implementations that currently include ATC as an additional coding may continue
			to do so,
			but should maintain the ability to map it to the classification extension, particularly
			for
			cross-border use.
		</p>
		<p> If ATC itself is used as the medication code (for example in certain <code>
			MedicationStatement</code> contexts), it should remain in <code>Medication.code</code>.
			ATC is not recommended for ingredient representation, as the code system lacks the
			required granularity. </p>
		<h4>Additional Information and Examples</h4><a>   </a>
		<p>
			Additional information and example instances can be found in the
			HL7 Europe Medication Prescription and Dispense Implementation Guide.
		</p>
	</div>
</div>